# 宽是好宽
How wide is this (sunshade)?
# 宽是4米
4 meters.
# 差不多
Good.
# 那就走你那边来撒 这里
How about I come over there.
# 来撒 你拉着头子撒
Do come. Take this corner.
# 我这样 我把它甩到这上面 等会来拉
Now I'll throw this up (this tree) so we can pull the shade up later.
# 拉来套（拴）在这底下
And we tie the end down there.
# 咿呀 我要是滚到这田头去要打得浇湿的哦
Eeya! I'd be soaking wet if I fell into this paddy field.
# 慢点 你鞋子是滑的 干脆把它脱了
Careful! You shoes are slippery. Better take them off.
# 下来 老子来
Get down. Leave it to me.
# 这绳子就合适噶 长短合适
This string is just right. Not too long and not too short.
# 使劲拉
Pull!
# 那里款（卡）起的
It gets stuck there.
# 伯爷那儿款起的
Uncle, it's stuck there.
# 够了够了
Good. Stop.
# 嘿 这个整起还要得四伯爷
Hei! This is already looking nice, isn't it uncle.
# 咋子要不得安
Of course.
# 那没得事我给你炒两个菜在这阴凉坝（吃）
How about sometime I cook some dish and you can enjoy under this shade.
# 老子啤酒都没得
I don't have any beer.
# 你要喝啥子啤酒我给你买就是
Any beer you want I can buy some for you.
# 有的是酒屋头
There are so many liquor stores.
# 有的是酒 伯娘说得对
We are never short of beer. Aunt is right.
# 就套在那里
Just tie it there.
# 这棵树上是不哦
On this tree?
# 在这里
Here.
# 要不要我给你掌（扶）一下哦
Do you need me holding the ladder?
# 掌啥子掌哦 老子是飞天蜈蚣
No need. I'm "Fei Tian Wu Gong" (literally "Flying Centipede").
# 你还多凶哦
You must be very ferocious.
# 那不是咋子
Definitely. What do you expect?
# 我给你甩上来哦
I'll throw it up.
# 甩嘛
Do it.
# 再站一梯上去嘛
Stand one step higher.
# 你再站一梯上去 矮很了
Take one step higher. You are too short.
# 我害怕
I'm afraid.
# 没得事的
Rest assured.
# 哪里害怕哦老子恩是
What are you afraid of?
# 我双手给你掌都的
I'm holding the ladder with both hands.
# 233米跳下来都不害怕
Jumping from 233 meters high doesn't scare me.
# 这丁点儿（高度）老子
This height isn't going to be any problem.
# 在这沟沟河头打烂船呐
I'm telling you there's nothing to be afraid of.
# 安逸撒
Isn't it nice?
# 安逸 可以
Nice. Good.
# 一哈子凉快了很多
Suddenly it feels cool.
# 搭了遮阳棚当然了
Of course. We have this sunshade.
# 狗东西麻雀儿
Bad sparrow.
# 雀儿窝得屎噶
Sparrow poop?
# 嗯
Yep.
# 二天炒菜炒啊炒得它要窝点屎来给你加点料
Maybe some day sparrows come and add some "flavoring" when you cook.
# 哈哈 加点佐料
Haha! Add some "seasoning".
# 这哈遮阳棚挡住了没得事的
Now this sunshade will protect us.
# 四伯爷还是可以哦
Uncle you are good.
# 可以可以
Good. Good.
# 还上得到台（面）了哈
Does it look proper?
# 嗯 可以
En. Good.
# 我给你炸个鲜奶嘛
Let me cook some Deep-fried Milk for you.
# 随便
Go ahead.
# 你是试这个灶的
You are testing this stove,
# 是不是嘛
aren't you?
# 买了两瓶 两瓶来做
We bought two bottles of milk for this.
# 拔鲜奶
Thread Milk
# 嘿嘿 拔鲜奶 炸鲜奶
Hehe. Thread Milk? Fried Milk.
# 哦
Oh.
# 炸鲜奶
Fried Milk
# 炸鲜奶哇
So it's Fried Milk.
# 哦
Oh.
# 就是你说炸来金黄金黄的那个呢
It's the thing you said was yellow and golden after frying.
# 啊
Ah.
# 倒两瓶
Let's pour both in.
# 你下次想吃（炸）酸奶也可以 纯牛奶也可以
Next time we can fry yogurt. Or whole-milk.
# 酸奶 酸的拿啥子来配呢
Yogurt? What goes with yogurt?
# 糖撒 甜的你吃得不嘛
Sugar. Can you eat sweet things?
# 甜的吃得
Yes, I can.
# 你看这里一斤鲜奶
Here we have 1 Jin (500g) fresh milk.
# 放这个淀粉
Add some corn starch.
# 这个包谷粉 玉米淀粉60克
60 grams of corn starch.
# 两勺 两勺多一点点
Two spoonful. And a little bit more.
# 吃甜点吗不吃嫩甜
Make it sweeter? Not too sweet.
# 不吃嫩甜 吃甜很了不安逸
Not too sweet. It's not good to have too much sugar.
# 差不多咯
That's enough.
# 不得 这个炸出来没得那么甜的
No, it's not that sweet after frying.
# 放五勺糖
Add five spoons of sugar.
# 把这个搅 搅匀了弄来煮
First stir and then boil after well mixed.
# 你这冷的（牛奶）白糖都化不了的嘛
Sugar isn't dissolving in cold (milk).
# 煮来它就要化的嘛
It will dissolve once I boil the milk.
# 走 我去开火
Let's go. I'll light the stove.
# 第一次（在家）弄哦 四伯爷
Uncle, this is the first time I cook (with this stove at home).
# 第一次弄技术要拿出来哦
Don't disappoint me this first time.
# 你不要跟他们说的希尔糊涂的整来不规则撒我要涛人哦
I'll chide you if you are not good at this after you've bragged so much.
# 你放心 害怕会让你涛人
Rest assured. I'm afraid of you scolding.
# 是撒 你整来不规则我就要涛你
Yes. I'll chide you if you are not good.
# 这哈就干起咯
We are starting now.
# 干起嘛 我看你咋子干的嘛
Go ahead. I'll watch you cook.
# 看到没 粘（稠）了
See? It turns thick.
# 煮粘了哒 煮粘了就可以了
Just cook until it's thick.
# 可以吃了哇
We can eat now?
# 这白白的
Look how white it is.
# 我摸哈看冷没有
Let me feel the temperature.
# 好想 就冷咯
It's turning cold.
# 再冰它哈儿就冷了 就跟它冰凉粉样
Let it cool a little bit longer. Just like cooling bean jelly.
# 四伯爷你看 这都冷了
Uncle look. It's cold now.
# 还可以撒 结了皮了噶
Is it good? Has it gelled?
# 啊 冷了
Ah. Yes.
# 一般结了皮了基本上就可以要得了
Usually it's good enough when it gels.
# 看嘛 直接就可以把它拿起来
See. I can take it out as a whole.
# 来了火的
It's well formed.
# 可以可以可以
Good. Good. Good.
# 直接弄来切
Let's cut.
# 哦哟 这个粘刀的
Oyo. It sticks to the knife.
# 粘刀的 拿纸擦哈
Sticks? Wipe it with some paper towel.
# 用点水
Get some water.
# 我们切这个要是粘刀的话就弄点水
Rinse the knife with some water if it sticks.
# 它有一点粘刀这个
It sticks a little bit.
# 那哈子就不粘了
Now it doesn't stick to the knife anymore.
# 好 又搞起水
Good. Rinse more.
# 好嘛 好好好
Good.
# 然后就是把它弄起
Now let's put it in a plate.
# 跟豆腐一样
It looks like Tofu.
# 把它分开 分开来裹
Seperate it apart to be coated later.
# 好
Good.
# 嘿 安逸安逸
Hei. Nice!
# 尝一坨看
Let me try a piece.
# 这哈都可以吃
It's eatable.
# 你那菜刀沾了生水的
You knife was rinsed with tap water.
# 不关事
No worries.
# 不吃不吃不吃 炸好了来吃
Nope. Nope. I want to eat it fried.
# 打两个蛋
Crack two eggs.
# 嘿打蛋这个技术还拿给你学到了的哒
Hei! You learned this cracking trick pretty well.
# 可以 你这个级别
Good. You are professional.
# 单手打蛋
Cracking eggs with one hand.
# 是啊 你打蛋的级别还是上等级别 我看一哈
Indeed! I can see you are "top-rated" at cracking the eggs.
# 我在视频头都看得到
I saw in videos where people
# 一敲手一捏就起来了
simply crack the egg and lift the shells up with one hand.
# 可以
Good.
# 可以噶
Looks good?
# 好 现在手套戴好了开始裹
Ok. Now we have disposable glove on. We can coat the milk.
# 然后再裹这个
Then coat with this.
# 可以撒
Good?
# 可以可以 嘿嘿安逸
Good. Hehe. Nice.
# 这个是啥子做的安
What is this?
# 这个是面包糠
This is breadcrumbs.
# 尝一哈看嘛
Let me take a bite.
# 是不是外面是脆的 里头还是嫩的
Isn't it crispy outside and tender inside?
# 安逸
Nice!
# 这个就是我跟你说的那个炸酸奶
This is the Deep-fried Yogurt I told you about.
# 鲜奶 不是酸奶
Fresh milk, not yogurt.
# 好吃好吃 外面有点硬 里头嫩咚咚的
It tastes good. Hard outside, but really tender inside.
# 安逸
Nice!
# 适合我们这些牙口不好的吃
It suits us who don't have strong teeth.
# 真的有点好吃
It really tastes good.
# 伯娘 过来吃
Aunt, come and try some.
# 哪个是好的嘛 这个
Which one tastes good? This one?
# 随便哪个都好的
Any of them tastes good.
# 嗯 好吃
Umm. Delicious.
# 这个吃了扛饿不呢
Does eating this ward off hunger?
# 扛饿
It does.
# 我直接用手拿了
I'm eating with my hands.
# 我再吃一坨
I want one more.
# 可以
Good.
# 老子二天干活路带点拿出去干可以撒
Can I take some when I go to work?
# 可以
Sure.
# 拿个胶纸纸装起
Take some in a plastic wrap.
# 安逸
Nice!
# 所以说我们在家里面有这种老人的话可以做点这个给他吃
So we can cook this dish for senior people at home.